<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gaurav Arora</title>
    <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gaurav Arora</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 18:11:03 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gauravaror.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Define</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/define/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 12:37:12 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/define/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of the concepts have one underlying idea and it&amp;rsquo;s worth noting those important ideas to remind myself about them later when I forget them. I try to keep them as brief as possible.
Mean Field approximation, bits, nats&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problems</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 18:11:03 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/problems/</guid>
      <description>Trapping Rain Water Kth Largest element in an array Linked List Cycle Solution
There are two type of solution for identifying Linked List cycle. First solution is to maintain the hash table of element seen till now and if you see an element again then you know linked list have cycles but this required O(n) space.
Better solution is to keep two pointers one fast and one slow. Fast pointer moves two element at a list and slow moves one element at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Educative patterns</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/educative_patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 20:18:52 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/educative_patterns/</guid>
      <description>Maintaining list Inspired from list maintained by sadihassan
Pattern : Sliding Window (07)    Title Link Code Notes     Fruits into baskets (medium) Leet github Sliding window, check at end of if condition    Pattern : Two pointers    Title Link Code Notes     Pair with Target Sum (easy) Leet github hashing solution and two pointers    Pattern : Fast and Slow pointers:    Title Link Code Notes     Linked list Cycle Leet github Fast and slow pointer and hash tables   Start of Linked list Cycle Leet github Fast and slow point approach and also hash based works works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attention</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 01:09:07 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/attention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Attention mechanism [1,2] improved NLP architectures by allowing them to focus on a relevant part of input/representation similar to how we humans do. While reading a text if the first and last character of a word is correct, humans can understand the text [3]. This post examines the inner working of additive and multiplicative attention, i.e. How attention mechanism converts query and hidden states into attention scores.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gradient estimation for hard non-linearities</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/straight_through_estimator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 01:12:48 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/straight_through_estimator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The hard non-linearities such as step functions are useful for modelling a categorical variable in neural networks. The gradient is zero everywhere for hard activations, which leads to difficulty in training using backpropagation. We review some technique proposed to estimate gradient such as straight through estimator.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory networks</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/memory_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 19:41:03 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/memory_networks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Memory Networks&lt;/code&gt; are neural networks which have access to explicit storage and a mechanism to access storage to answer query requiring multi-hop reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;https://gauravaror.github.io/css/hugo-easy-gallery.css&#34; /&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;box&#34; style=&#34;max-width:40%&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figure  itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; src=&#34;https://gauravaror.github.io/Big_Oak.png&#34; alt=&#34;/Big_Oak.png&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://gauravaror.github.io/Big_Oak.png&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running list of interesting links</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/interesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 10:39:07 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/interesting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Below is a running list of interesting articles/StackOverflow answers which seems worth sharing and referring back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WIP:A short tour of libpst</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/libpst/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 17:45:50 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/libpst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;libpst&lt;/code&gt; is a library to extract text from microsoft properitery format &lt;code&gt;.pst&lt;/code&gt;, which is used to storing emails, attachments. There isn&amp;rsquo;t a good documentation for &lt;code&gt;libpst&lt;/code&gt;.
This is a simple tour writing a &lt;code&gt;c++&lt;/code&gt; program from scratch to extract an email and it&amp;rsquo;s attachment from &lt;code&gt;.pst&lt;/code&gt; file using &lt;code&gt;libpst&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear to Quadratic and back</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/linear_quadratic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 21:37:37 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/linear_quadratic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can a single for loop be running with quadratic time complexity?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xapian</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/xapian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 16:14:09 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/xapian/</guid>
      <description>I offer commercial development support for Xapian since 2014. I have developed the following capabilities in Xapian commercially:
 Decoupled indexing and text extraction, which drastically reducing indexing time. Enabled indexing of images using tesseract. I have designed and implemented a heuristic algorithm to extract table from images. I have implemented the Language Modelling based ranking scheme in Xapian (GSOC). I have developed an evaluation framework for Xapian.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 13:15:04 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I am Gaurav Arora. I am pursuing a Masters of Science (Computer Science) under the supervision of Prof. Timothy Baldwin. My master&amp;rsquo;s research project focuses on Catastrophic Forgetting in Neural Networks. Our empirical study comparing different architecture like CNN, and LSTM for forgetting was accepted in ALTA 2019.
I have been offering consultancy services for Xapianfrom 2014. Please find a list of my Xapian related projects here. I was a Google Summer of Code Intern with Xapian in 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gdb Demystified</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 16:29:48 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gdb&lt;/strong&gt; is one of the useful commands to debug what&amp;rsquo;s going wrong with your program.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>