<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gaurav Arora</title>
    <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gaurav Arora</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 21:37:37 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gauravaror.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear to Quadratic and back</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/linear_quadratic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 21:37:37 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/linear_quadratic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can a single for loop be running with quadratic time complexity?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xapian</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/xapian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 16:14:09 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/xapian/</guid>
      <description>I offer commercial development support for Xapian since 2014. I have developed the following capabilities in Xapian commercially:
 Decoupled indexing and text extraction, which drastically reducing indexing time. Enabled indexing of images using tesseract. I have designed and implemented a heuristic algorithm to extract table from images. I have implemented the Language Modelling based ranking scheme in Xapian (GSOC). I have developed an evaluation framework for Xapian.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 13:15:04 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I am Gaurav Arora. I am pursuing a Masters of Science (Computer Science) under the supervision of Prof. Timothy Baldwin. My master&#39;s research project focuses on Catastrophic Forgetting in Neural Networks. Our empirical study comparing different architecture like CNN, and LSTM for forgetting was accepted in ALTA 2019.
I have been offering consultancy services for Xapianfrom 2014. Please find a list of my Xapian related projects here. I was a Google Summer of Code Intern with Xapian in 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gdb Demystified</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 16:29:48 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gdb&lt;/strong&gt; is one of the useful commands to debug what&#39;s going wrong with your program.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>