<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gaurav Arora</title>
    <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gaurav Arora</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 16:14:09 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gauravaror.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Xapian</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/xapian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 16:14:09 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/xapian/</guid>
      <description>I offer commerical development support for Xapian since 2014. I have developed following capabolities in Xapian commerically:
  Decoupled indexing and text extraction which reduced indexing time for 1 million images from several days to a few hours.  Enabled indexing of images using Optixal Character Recognition (OCR).   Designed and implemented a heuristic algorithm to extract table from images. IBM used this module for fraud detection on images and pdfs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 13:32:30 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/news/</guid>
      <description>  Oct 22, 2019 &amp;nbsp; Paper accepted at ALTA 2019   Jul 23, 2018 &amp;nbsp; Started MS (CS) at The University of Melbourne with Prof. Timothy Baldwin  and Afshin Rahimi   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 13:15:04 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I am Gaurav Arora. I am pursuing Masters of Science (Computer Science) under supervision of Prof. Timothy Baldwin. My research project in masters is focused on Catastrophic Forgetting in Neural Networks. We conducted a empirical study comparing different architecture like CNN, LSTM for forgetting. This work was recently published in ALTA 2019.
I have been offering consultancy services for Xapian  from 2014. All my xapian related projects are listed on this page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First</title>
      <link>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 16:29:48 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gauravaror.github.io/posts/first/</guid>
      <description>This is my first post now rendered with hugo css error.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>